autochartist.com 2014-06-30

# Privacy Policy | Autochartist

**Our Commitment**  
We recognise that your privacy is very important to you.  
This Privacy Policy discloses how the personal information you provide to us and our representatives, is collected, used, held, disclosed and disseminated.

We collect certain personal information from you for the purposes of:

  * Providing you with the relevant product or service
  * Managing and administering the product or service
  * Protecting against fraud

This policy is updated from time to time and we encourage you to check our website regularly for any updates to our Privacy Policy.

**Your Personal Information**  
Detailed below is some of the information we may hold on you:  
Name, address, telephone number(s), Date of birth, Email address, Occupation and job title, Transaction details associated with your trading through our broker clients. We do not store any credit card information.

**How We Collect Personal Information**  
We collect personal information in a number of ways, including:  
directly from you, by telephone, a data collection form; via an email or the internet.

**How We Use Your Personal Information**  
Primarily, your personal information is used in order to:

  * Meet particular legislative and regulatory requirements;
  * To assist in providing services to you;
  * To assist with any calls you make to us;
  * To communicate relevant information to you;
  * For our product development, marketing, planning, administration and credit control procedures.

From time to time, we may provide you with direct marketing material. This will include emails, articles and newsletters that may be of interest to you. If, at any time, you do not wish to receive this information any further, you may contact us with this request. We will endeavour to meet your request within 2 weeks.

**When We Disclose Your Personal Information**  
In line with modern business practices common to many institutions and to meet your specific needs we may disclose your personal information to statutory authorities and to parties outside of our group of companies. The organisations to which we disclose information may include:

  * other product providers in order to manage or administer your product or service;
  * compliance consultants to ensure that we, and our representatives are, meeting our compliance standards;
  * our group companies and associates;
  * information technology service providers to maintain, review and develop our business systems, procedures and infrastructure including testing or upgrading our computer systems;
  * government and regulatory authorities and other organisations, as required or authorised by law, for example, to government or regulatory bodies for the purposes related to public health or safety, the prevention or detection of unlawful activities or to protect public revenue.
  * a potential purchaser/organisation involved in the proposed sale of our business for the purpose of due diligence, corporate re-organisation and transfer or all or part of the assets of our business.
  * Parties to whom you have given your consent including your legal advisers;
  * a new owner of our business that will require the transfer of your personal information.

Our employees and the outsourcing companies/contractors are obliged to respect the confidentiality of any personal information held by us.

We take our obligations to protect your information seriously, this includes when we operate globally, as part of our operations some uses and disclosures of your information may occur outside your State or Territory.

In the event of that we propose to sell the business, we may disclose your personal information to potential purchasers for the purpose of them conducting due diligence investigations. Disclosure will be made in confidence and it will be a condition of that disclosure that no personal information will be used or disclosed by them.

**How We Store and Secure Your Personal Information**  
Your personal information may be held on our computer database. All computer-based information is protected through the use of access passwords. Data is backed up regularly and stored securely off site. Your client file is accessible to authorised personnel only and are appropriately secured out of hours. Other measures taken are:

  * Confidentiality requirements for our employees
  * Security measures for systems access
  * Providing a discreet environment for confidential discussions
  * Personal information will be treated as confidential information and sensitive information will be treated highly confidential. It is a legislative requirement that we keep all personal information and records for a period of 7 years. Should you cease to be a client of ours, we will maintain your personal information on or off site in a secure manner for 7 years. After this, the information may be destroyed.

**Ensure Your Personal Information Is Correct**  
We take all reasonable precautions to ensure that the personal information we collect, use and disclose is accurate, complete and up-to- date. To ensure we can maintain this level of accuracy and completeness, we recommend that you:

  * inform us of any errors in your personal information as soon as possible; and
  * update us with any changes to your personal information as soon as possible.
  * Access to Your Personal Information

You have a right to access your personal information, subject to certain exceptions allowed by law. We ask that you provide your request for access in writing (for security reasons) and we will provide you with access to that personal information. Access to the requested personal information may include:

  * providing you with copies;
  * providing you with the opportunity for inspection; or providing you with a summary.
  * If charges are applicable in providing access to you, we will disclose these charges to you prior to providing you with the information.

Some exceptions exist where we will not provide you with access to your personal information if:

  * providing access would pose a serious threat to the life or health of a person;
  * providing access would have an unreasonable impact on the privacy of others;
  * the request for access is frivolous or vexatious;
  * the information is related to existing or anticipated legal proceedings between us and would not be discoverable in those proceedings;
  * providing access would reveal our intentions in relation to negotiations with you in such a way as to prejudice those negotiations;
  * providing access would be unlawful;
  * denying access is required or authorised by or under law;
  * providing access would be likely to prejudice certain operations by or on behalf of an enforcement body or an enforcement body requests that access not be provided on the grounds of national security.

Should we refuse you access to your personal information, we will provide you with a written explanation for that refusal.

**Using Government Identifiers**  
We do not collect government identifiers such as your tax file number, Medicare number or pension card number.

**Dealing with us anonymously**  
You can deal with us anonymously where it is lawful and practicable to do so. For example, if you telephone requesting our postal address.

**Your sensitive information**  
Without your consent we will not collect information about you that reveals your racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs or afflations, membership of professional or trade association, membership of a trade union, details of health, disability, sexual orientation, or criminal record.

This is subject to some exceptions including:

  * the collection is required by law; and
  * when the information is necessary for the establishment, exercise or defence of a legal claim.

**Complaints Resolutions**  
Please contact our Legal Department if you wish to complain about any breach or potential breach of your privacy rights. Your complaint will be responded to within 7 days.

**Our Website**  
The autochartist.com website provides links to third party websites. The use of your information by these third party sites is not within our control and we cannot and do not accept responsibility for the conduct of these organisations. Other websites are not subject to our privacy standards, policies and procedures. You will need to contact or review those websites directly to ascertain their privacy stands, policies and procedures.

You may register with us to receive newsletters and other information. By doing so, your name and email address will be collected and stored on our database. We take care to ensure that the personal information you give us on our website is protected. For example, our website has electronic security systems in place, including the use of firewalls and data encryption.

If you do not wish to receive any further information from us, or you wish to update your registration details, please email your request to us. We will endeavour to meet your request within two weeks.

We may use cookie technology as part of our websites statistical reporting. A cookie is a small piece of information sent by a website that is saved on your hard disk by your computer’s browser. It holds information a site may need to personalise your experience and to gather web site statistical data, such as which pages are visited, what is downloaded, the internet provider’s domain name and country that our visitors come from and the addresses of sites visited immediately before, and after, coming to our site. However, none of this is associated with you as an individual. It is measured only in aggregate. The information in the cookies lets us trace your “click stream” activity (i.e., the paths taken by visitors to our site as they move from page to page.) Cookies do not capture your individual email address or any private information about you.

We also use standard web server log files to help us count visitors and evaluate our site’s technical capacity. We use this information to find out how many people visit our site, help us arrange the pages in the most user-friendly way, keep the site browser-friendly, and to make our pages more useful to our visitors. We record information on site traffic but not information on individual visitors to our site, so no information about you in particular will be kept or used.

**Internal Procedure for dealing with communications**  
The three key steps we follow are:

Consent – Only commercial electronic messages are sent with the addressee’s consent – either express or inferred consent.

Identify – Electronic messages will include clear and accurate information about the person and the company that is responsible for sending the commercial electronic message.

Unsubscribe – We ensure that a functional unsubscribe facility is included in all our commercial electronic messages and deal with unsubscribe requests promptly.

**Age sensitive communication**  
Where the content of a Commercial Communication seeks to promote or inspire interaction with a product, service or event that is age sensitive, we take reasonable steps to ensure that such content is sent to Recipients who are legally entitled to use or participate in the product service or event.

**Contact Details**  
Email: [legal@autochartist.com](mailto:legal@autochartist.com)
